

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, Oracle Pl Sql



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer -Oracle PL

SQL

Current Company: Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd

Current Location: Gurgaon

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Hyderabad, Gurgaon

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: SQL,PL/SQL,Oracle,Toad

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21 Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

## Summary

7+ years of experience in the IT industry as Software Engineer and have a good exposure over technologies like SQL PL/SQL, Oracle BI Publisher report, Oracle Utilities (CC&B), Oracle Utility Meter Data Management(MDM), VB.Net, C#.Net and Regression Testing. Sound knowledge of designing advanced SQL query on Oracle Database, creating PL/SQL scripts, Procedure, Function, Triggers, Cursors, Objects, Tables, View, Synonyms and all database objects.

# Work Experience

Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd as Senior Software Engineer -Oracle PL SQL

Jul 2017 to Till Date

Project Name: CIO Accenture Internal project

Worked with the team as tester and involve in small development at database level. Project was totally based on Agile/Scrum Methodology and is completely Accenture internal project for maintaining all applications provision to users at one place .Creating test cases, developing testing plans and identifying use cases. Testing done at QA, UAT envs. level.

Designation: Senior Software Engineer (JUL-2017-To Aug-19)

Project Info: British UK multinational company

Had an Openlink Endur application bootcamp training for 6 months which was based on trading domain then moved to a project based on it and worked with regression testing team . Responsible for regression testing .used to run EOD tasks considering two env. parallely Pre and Post and generate the reports from both env. to compare it with beyond beyond compare tool and analysing the changes created on the application. Implementing test cases, developing testing plans and identifying use cases.

**HCL TECHNOLOGIES** as Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2016 to Jun 2017

Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Project Name: IKEA

Worked with support team in IKEA retail domain project as senior support engineer. Involved in solving the incident raised

by users through BMC remedy tool.

Also handled the Quality management of project every month.

Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Project Name: A-RAPDRP

Worked with Data Migration team in ARAPDRP power domain project as a PI/SQL developer. Involved in loading the csv file of data given by client to oracle database through SQL loader. Written different scripts to refine data according to business logic, going through various stages to move it to production oracle database.

#### Vayam Technologies as Software Engineer

May 2012 to Apr 2016

Project Name: Providing & Implementation of Operational Automation Systems for Power, Commercial & Electricity Department and Other Departments of NDMC.

Worked as Software Engineer (ERP Practice) in Vayam Technologies Ltd. & actively taking part in implementing Oracle Utilities Meter Data Management for client NDMC (New Delhi Municipal Council) for their Electricity, Water & Property Tax Billing & other customer related activities. Developing all kind of Reports using Oracle BI Publisher and PL/SQL. Also, responsible for creating different database objects like table, view, procedure, function, cursor etc. to implement different business logics.

Worked on .Net platform to fulfill the requirement of client (using language VB).

Role: PL/SQL Developer

Developed database objects like Stored Procedures, Functions, Packages and Triggers using SQL and PL/SQL to implement different business logics.

Developed materialized views for data replication in distributed environments.

Created Tables, Views, Constraints, Indexes.

Effectively made use of Table Functions, Indexes, Table Partitioning, Collections, Analytical functions.

Good knowledge on logical and physical Data Modeling using normalizing Techniques.

Experience in SQL performance tuning.

Role: Oracle BI Publisher Developer

Developed all kinds of reports required by NDMC using Oracle BI Publisher, MS-word (for designing templates) and Oracle Utility.

Developed several detailed and summary reports and sub reports according to business requirements using Oracle BI Publisher table wizard.

Developed several heavy reports using event trigger functionality through Data Template data set type.

Role: .Net Developer

Developed several forms in existing application according to the requirement of the client.

Made the changes in existing code according to the requirement of the client for implementing new business logics.

Re-designed the existing forms to give attractive look.

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from Uttar Pradesh Technical University (UPTU) in 2010

#### IT Skills

| Skill Name                 | Version Last Used Experience |
|----------------------------|------------------------------|
| Oracle 9i/10g/11g          |                              |
| Toad, Oracle SQL Developer |                              |
| Oracle PL/SQL developer    |                              |

## Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English  |             |      |       |       |
| Hindi    |             |      |       |       |

# **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

# **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time